<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog Multiplier</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/analog_multiplier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/analog_multiplier/</guid>
      <description>Designed and implemented a 4-bit multiplier using CMOS transistors in LTSpice.
We ran tests for different logic gates and optimized the multiplicities of the nMOS and pMOS transistors to ensure that the constructed logic gates were outputting strong logical highs and strong logical lows.
From these logic gates, we then constructed a 1-bit full adder, a 4-bit full adder, and then a 4-bit multiplier. We measured the voltage transfer characteristics at all the steps and propogation delays in order to calculate the fastest clock speed possible for the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASL Translation Using Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/asl_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/asl_detection/</guid>
      <description>A partner and I used a classic facial recognition algorithm we implemented from researchh papers to translate American Sign Language. We provided the algorithm with a huge training data set (several gigabytes) and took photos of ourselves spelling out the letters of the alphabet. So far, the program allows the user to type in a word, the algorithm picks (at random) one of the test images for each letter we took of ourselves, and outputs what word it is that it thinks we are spelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assembly Chrome Dinosaur Game</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/assembly_dinosaur_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/assembly_dinosaur_game/</guid>
      <description>I designed and built a preliminary version of a game inspired by the chrome dinosaur game written in MIPS assembly. The entire game can be exported to 32-bit binary instructions that can be run on the single cycle cpu built in verilog as a part of another project.
The functionality the game holds is:
 user jumps over cacti using the keyboard game ends if user comes into contact with cactus speed of cactus generation increases with play time  I created this game as an individual for a computer architecture class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCI Spatial Filtering Algorithms</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/topics_in_bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/topics_in_bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my topics in bioengineering class, I took a deep dive into problems with EEG based brain computer interfaces. A huge issue is the artifacts that are created and lower than ideal spatial resolution. I researched ICA, CSP, and other spatial filters. To see my presentation and report, click the link to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boat Design For Specific Angle of Vanishing Stability</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/boats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/boats/</guid>
      <description>In this project, a partner and I designed a mathematically defined boat to calculate the angle of vanishing stability for it. Then, we CADded the ribs, laser cut them, shrink wrapped the boat, and tested it. All calculations were done in mathematica and CAD models were created using SolidWorks.
To read the full report and explanation of the math behind it, click the link on the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Tools For Safe Consumption Site Advocates</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/uocd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/uocd/</guid>
      <description>I worked with safe consumption site advocates in the Boston area to design a tool that could potentially revolutionize the current state of safe consumption sites in the U.S. today. This project was done in a team of four and over a semester through a user oriented collaborative design class.
The severity of the opioid epidemic today was shocking to see and we all really wanted to do something about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential Drive with NEATOs</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/differential_drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/differential_drive/</guid>
      <description>I used the concept of differential drive to command a NEATO across a bridge that can be defined by a parametric curve function. I used ROS in order to send velocity commands to the NEATOs.
To learn more about the math behind it and the errors between what actually happened and what was projected to happen click the link on the left.
To watch a video of this in action: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health Conscious Scheduling Application</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/autem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/autem/</guid>
      <description>Many college students and people in the workforce are pushing themselves in this never ending rat race which can be a huge detriment to their mental health. Olin likes to use the term &amp;ldquo;overscoping your life&amp;rdquo; to describe this phenomenon. This application aims to help people avoid this by using the premise that people are actually more likely to be productive when they take breaks and complete activities that make themselves happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Just Dance</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/just_dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/just_dance/</guid>
      <description>A partner and I created a game where a user completes certain dance moves after we show them what to complete, and we score them on how well they dance and check if they are dancing the correct move. This algorithm uses:
 accelerometer data FFT cross correlation signal aligning techniques  To read more about the algorithm and how the game works, click the link to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personable Robot</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/poe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/poe/</guid>
      <description>As a part of a principles of engineering class, I built a small, personable robot that wandered the halls of Olin College&#39;s academic center and said hi to people. This was done as a part of a 4 person team over half a semester. My personal contributions were firmware, and programming how the robot would react to its surroundings. I also used agile scrum to plan out the project and built the final documentation website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Candidate Summaries From Twitter</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/twitter_scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/twitter_scraping/</guid>
      <description>As there were many presedential candidates in the beginning of the 2020 presidential election, it was hard to keep up with what everyone was saying and what everyone stood for individually. Acknowledging that twitter had become the most common form of political communication directly from candidates, I gathered tweets and picked out the words that were most associated with each candidate.
For more information on the algorithm and tools used click on the link to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Cycle CPU</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/single_cycle_cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/single_cycle_cpu/</guid>
      <description>I designed and implemented a MIPS compliant single cycle CPU. It used a 32-bit architecture. This CPU is capable of completing the following assembly commands:
 load word store word add add immediate subtract set less than xor immediate jump register jump and link jump branch equal branch not equal  I worked on this project individually over the course of 2 weeks as a part of the computer architecture class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLSI Circuit Optimization Using Discrete Math</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/vlsi_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/vlsi_project/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my discrete math class, a project partner and I conducted research into how VLSI circuits can be optimized using Euler paths. We looked into how to represent MOS transistor circuits as logic graphs. We also designed an algorithm to simplify logic graphs that are excessively complicated which can then be turned into electrical layouts in silicon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>